Lisa Piercey, MD, MBA, FACHE

Lisa.Piercey@novastone-ca.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Nationally recognized physician executive with extensive experience in healthcare operations across ambulatory, inpatient, and post-acute care settings, as well as health policy, state and federal government relations, public health, value-based care, and licensing and regulation. Emphasis throughout career on access to care in rural and vulnerable populations. Excels at strategy and vision, negotiation, and crisis management and communication.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration, Bethel University, Nashville, TN – **2009 Residency in Pediatrics,** East Tennessee State University Quillen COM, Johnson City, TN – **2005 Internship in Pediatrics,** East Tennessee State University Quillen COM, Johnson City, TN – **2003 Doctor of Medicine,** East Tennessee State University Quillen COM, Johnson City, TN – **2002 Bachelor of Science in Chemistry,** Lipscomb University, Nashville, TN – **1998**

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Founder and CEO, Tristela Capital Partners, LLC

2023 - present

Nashville, TN – Physician-led rural healthcare search fund in partnership with Novastone Capital Advisors

Founder and CEO, Tristela Strategies, LLC

2022 - present

Nashville, TN – Boutique strategic advisory firm for healthcare investors and operators

Commissioner, Tennessee Department of Health

2019 - 2022

Nashville, TN – Cabinet appointment to lead agency with \$690M budget and 4,300 employees in 114 locations

- Served as lead Cabinet advisor and strategist for state's COVID-19 response on Governor's Unified Command, with Department of Military and TN Emergency Management, provided ongoing health guidance across national and international media platforms. Represented state health officials in multiple interactions with White House during two presidential administrations, as well as served on testing, vaccine, and therapeutics workgroups with CDC, FDA, HHS, and private sector laboratory and pharmaceutical corporations.
- Directed 89 public health clinics with 56 primary care locations, including FQHCs and RHCs, and 34 dental clinics, serving as the state's largest safety net provider. Spearheaded a multi-year revenue cycle and operational efficiency improvement strategy, including addition of statewide primary care telehealth network and new electronic health record procurement and conversion.
- Established state's first-ever public/private dental access workgroup with dental schools, payors, and private sector, to bolster dental workforce pipeline, expand dental access for underserved populations, and optimize provider reimbursement, through \$94M, five-year Healthy Smiles initiative.

Executive Vice President, West Tennessee Healthcare

2015 - 2019

Jackson, TN-Nation's 9 th largest public, not-for-profit health system with 7,000+employees and \$1B annual revenue

- Carried out the full range of strategic and operational planning and management for all of health system's rural and suburban hospitals 5 acute care, 2 inpatient rehab, 1 psychiatric hospital with combined 534 beds including executive leadership through acquisition of three hospitals from for-profit competitor.
- Provided administrative management of all post-acute care services for entire market, including skilled nursing, infusion centers, durable medical equipment (DME), and home health joint venture.
- Designed and executed first-of-its-kind chronic disease management program with over 70% reduction in participant readmissions; developed and launched corporate wellness/occupational health service line.

Vice-President, Physician Services, West Tennessee Healthcare

2013 - 2015

• Provided executive operational and strategic oversight of West Tennessee Medical Group, with practice administration for approximately 80 providers (60 physicians, 20 midlevels) encompassing 15 outpatient clinics, 6 inpatient/surgical service lines, and 4 hospitalist practices.

Vice-President, Hospital Services, West Tennessee Healthcare

2011 - 2013

- Led the design, construction, staffing, and programming for LIFT Wellness Center, a \$28M internationally acclaimed 82,000-sq ft medical fitness facility, with co-located urgent care and therapy clinics, in partnership with surrounding mixed-use retail/residential development.
- Provided oversight for all SportsPlus Rehab Centers, offering comprehensive services for physical, occupational, speech, and aquatic therapy in 13 outpatient facilities. Spearheaded year-long \$1.2M revenue cycle improvement project and opened three new clinic locations.
- Restructured and negotiated contract for all hospital-based food services and retail franchise outlets, resulting in sustained revenue growth and annual cost savings of over \$900K.

Assistant Medical Director, Jackson Madison County General Hospital

2009 - 2011

- Introduced and implemented computerized physician order entry (CPOE) for Cerner electronic health record.
- Established provider education program and web-based screening tool for early recognition of diabetes.
- Spearheaded electronic conversion of case management process for tracking and optimizing length of stay.

Medical Director, Child Maltreatment Program, Vanderbilt Children's Hospital

2007 - 2010

- Developed and implemented a system for multi-disciplinary review of all suspected child abuse cases and created an online learning portal to facilitate provider access to the most current and comprehensive literature regarding child maltreatment.
- Expanded didactic instruction for nursing, faculty, administrators, medical students, residents, and community agencies.
- Procured first-ever photodocumentation system and conducted training for faculty and residents in forensic photography.

Medical Director, Madison County Child Advocacy Center

2006 - present

- Collaborated with medical providers, educators, and IT experts to develop and implement a statewide peer review network of child abuse as a means for improving quality and providing continuing education.
- Procured digital video colposcopy system and established a streamlined system for coordinating child abuse medical evaluations with emergency, laboratory, and forensic services.

Director, Child Protection Team, Jackson Madison County General Hospital

2006 - present

- Created and implemented a Child Protection Response Team providing rapid evaluation and reporting of suspected child maltreatment.
- Developed protocols for efficiently and thoroughly evaluating infants and children presenting for suspected abuse, including policies for radiologic assessments, anogenital examinations under conscious sedation, and standardized reporting.
- Partnered with the local police department for additional training for a newly created Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner program.

General Pediatrician, The Jackson Clinic

2005 - 2010

• Examined, diagnosed, and treated infants and children, as well as instituted quality improvements and new billing system. Executed first-ever pediatric group wellness event and training.

2000 201

Lisa Piercey, MD, MBA, FACHE RESUME February 2023– Page 3

CREDENTIALS

American Board of Pediatrics, Child Abuse Pediatrics board certification	2013 – present
American College of Healthcare Executives, Fellow	2013 - present
American Board of Pediatrics, General Pediatrics board certification	2005 - present
State of Tennessee Medical License, TN #38119	2003 - present

AWARDS/RECOGNITIONS

Delta Dental of TN Smile Power Award	2022
ETSU QCOM Alumni Outstanding Achievement in Medicine	2022
Nashville Post "In Charge" Healthcare Power Brokers	2022
ACHE Regent Excellence Award for Diversity & Justice	2021
TCCY John Seigenthaler Media Award	2021
Project CURE Healthcare Hero Award	2021
Bethel University Alumni Service Award	2021
TMA/TPHA William Schaffner Public Health Hero Award	2020
Natl Academy of Television Arts Emmy Nominations (3)	2020
Jonah Affordable Housing Healthcare Award	2020
East TN State University Distinguished Alumni Award	2019
Lipscomb University JS Ward Society Hero of Science Award	2019
TN Primary Care Assoc. Executive Leadership Award	2019
Jackson Business & Professional Women Sterling Award	2019
WestStar Jimmy Daniel Make-A-Difference Award	2018
THA/ACHE Rural Healthcare Executive of the Year	2017
THA/ACHE Senior Healthcare Executive of the Year	2016
JAAACC Outstanding Woman in Business	2015
Jackson Sun's Forty Under 40	2014
Jackson's Finest Young Professionals	2011
Tennessee Women's Journal IMPACT Award	2011
Jackson Sun Readers' Choice Award – Best Pediatrician	2009
Child Protection Investigative Team Excellence Award	
Jackson Sun Readers' Choice Award – Best Pediatrician	2008

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Commandant's National Security Program, US Army War College	2022
Leadership Tennessee, Lipscomb University	2019
Council Fellows Program, Nashville Health Care Council	2018
WestStar Leadership Development Program, University of TN Martin	2015
Leadership Jackson , Jackson Area Chamber of Commerce	2011